Guide to the T. S. Ferree, Jr. Papers, 1940-1989 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
T. S. Ferree, Jr. papers 1940-1989 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Ferree, T. S. (Thaddeus S.) Jr., d. 1990.
8.0 linear feet Extent: 3000 Items
T. S. Ferree Jr. was a commercial artist, graphic designer and advertising executive based in Raleigh, N.C. The T. S. Ferree, Jr. Papers span the years 1940-1989 and include drawings and sketches, proofs and tear sheets of printed advertisements, clippings, photographs, slides, speeches, brochures and pamphlets, direct marketing mailers and collateral literature that document Ferree's and the Ferree Studios' advertising and commercial design work. Clients consist mainly of businesses located in the Virginia-North Carolina-South Carolina tri-state region, including Branch Banking and Trust (BB&T), BTR Management, Ciba-Geigy, General Electric, McLean Trucking, Newport News Shipbuilding, Reckitt Benckiser (Glass Plus, Spray 'n Wash), Smith Transfer Company, Sweetheart Cups (Maryland Cup Corporation), Tobacco Associates and The Washington Group. The collection also includes materials relating to the Ferree School of Art, the Raleigh Ad Club, and the Advertising Federation of America. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00389
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The T. S. Ferree, Jr. Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993.
Biographical Note
T. S. Ferree Jr. was born circa 1922 near Ashboro, N.C. and educated at N.C. State College, the American Academy and Art Institute of Chicago. He opened Ferree Studios in 1934, serving primarily advertising agencies in Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Tennessee. During World War II he served as Consultant on Health Education for the Surgeon General, producing printed materials on tropical and venereal diseases. In 1947 he opened the Ferree School of Art which he operated until 1953. Ferree was active in Toastmasters and regional advertising organizations, serving a term as District Governor for the Advertising Federation of America. His design for the North Carolina Bicentennial medallion won a competition sponsored by the Franklin Mint.
Collection Overview
The T. S. Ferree, Jr. Papers span the years 1940-1989 and include drawings and sketches, proofs and tear sheets of printed advertisements, clippings, photographs, slides, speeches, brochures and pamphlets, direct marketing mailers and collateral literature that document Ferree's and the Ferree Studios' advertising and commercial design work. Clients consist mainly of businesses located in the Virginia-North Carolina-South Carolina tri-state region, including Branch Banking and Trust (BB&T), BTR Management, Ciba-Geigy, General Electric, McLean Trucking, Newport News Shipbuilding, Reckitt Benckiser (Glass Plus, Spray 'n Wash), Smith Transfer Company, Sweetheart Cups (Maryland Cup Corporation), Tobacco Associates and The Washington Group. The collection also includes materials relating to the Ferree School of Art, the Raleigh Ad Club, and the Advertising Federation of America.
Collection Arrangement
Arranged into the following series: General Files, Ferree Studios Promotional Materials, Production Examples, and Oversize Materials.
Subject Headings
Ferree, T.S. (Thaddeus S.), Jr., d. 1990; Advertising Federation of America; Branch Banking and Trust Company; CIBA-GEIGY Corporation; General Electric Company; Maryland Cup Corporation; McLean Trucking Company; Newport News Shipbuilding and Dry Dock Company; Reckitt Benckiser (Firm); Washington Group International; Advertising; Advertising -- Design; Advertising -- History; Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- United States -- Design; Advertising -- United States -- History; Advertising, Direct-mail; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- United States; Art schools; Art schools -- United States; Commercial art; Commercial art -- United States; Commercial artists; Commercial artists -- United States; Graphic arts; Graphic arts -- United States; Proofs; Photographs; Slides; North Carolina -- Commerce; South Carolina -- Commerce; Virginia -- Commerce; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Ben Rosen Papers
Charles McKinney Papers
Gene Federico Papers
Howard Scott Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Anthony J. Viola Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. John F. Dignam Papers
Lester Wunderman Papers
Lore Parker Papers
Robert S. Smith Papers
Sheldon B. Sosna Papers
Detailed Description of Collection
- General Files, 1950-1983 and undated, (1 box)
  - T. S. Ferree, Jr. biographical materials, undated (Box 1)
  - Advertising Federation of America (AFA), 1964 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1975 (Box 1)
  - Ferree School of Art, 1950-1952 (Box 1)
  - Raleigh Ad Club, 1983 and undated (Box 1)
  - Suttles (Bill): billing examples and correspondence, circa 1978 (Box 1)
  - Speeches
    - Gold Medal Award, 1964 (Box 1)
    - How to Get Along With an Artist, undated (Box 1)
    - PTA, Mount Vernon School, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Raleigh revitalization, undated (Box 1)
    - Sertoma Club, 1959 (Box 1)
- Ferree Studios Promotional Materials, 1947-1982 and undated, (1 box)
  - Logos, undated (Box 1)
  - Mailings, undated (Box 1)
  - Portfolios and booklets, undated, (3 folders) (Box 1)
  - Sample sketches, 1985 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Studio services outline, 1968 (Box 1)
  - T. S. Ferree Jr. examples of art including early work, 1947-1982 and undated (Box 1)
- Production Examples, 1947-1988 and undated, (5 boxes)
  - Booklets
    - 27605.0505, undated (Box 2)
    - Aeroglide, undated (Box 2)
    - Aerotron, undated (Box 2)
    - Alderman, undated (Box 2)
    - Aluminum Ladder Company, undated (Box 2)
    - American Diabetes Association, Select-A-Meal, 1978 (Box 2)
    - American Tobacco Company, Lucky Strike, undated (Box 2)
    - Amoco, undated (Box 2)
    - Apparel, Inc., undated (Box 2)
    - Aqua-Aid, undated (Box 2)
    - Association for N.C. Regional Medical Program, Select-A-Meal, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Baptist State Convention, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Barnett Bank, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Bassett-Walker, 1968 (Box 2)
    - BB&T (Branch Banking and Trust), 1965 and undated (Box 2)
    - Bluegill Tackle, undated (Box 2)
    - BTR management, undated (Box 2)
    - Carolina Population Center, undated (Box 2)
    - Carolina Power & Light, 1947, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Carolina Solar Systems, undated (Box 2)
    - Cavalier Hotel, undated (Box 2)
    - CCB (Central Carolina Bank), circa 1963 (Box 2)
    - Charles Wm. Holland, undated (Box 2)
    - Ciba-Geigy, 1970-1976 (Box 2)
    - City of Raleigh, N.C., 1965-1967 and undated (Box 2)
    - Coachette, undated (Box 2)
    - Colonial Williamsburg, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Colorcraft, undated (Box 2)
    - Consolidated Shoe, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Country House, undated (Box 2)
    - Daniel International, undated (Box 2)
    - Deer Creek (Smith Williams & Associates), undated (Box 2)
    - D.R. Allen & Son, undated (Box 2)
    - Duff-Norton, undated (Box 2)
    - Exide Electronics, 1989 and undated (Box 2)
    - FCX (Farmers' Chemical Association), annual report, 1975 (Box 2)
    - Fieldcrest Mills, undated (Box 2)
    - Financial Fitness, Inc. (Occidental Life), undated (Box 2)
    - First Securities, undated (Box 2)
    - Fishel & Taylor, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Gauld Equipment, undated (Box 2)
    - General Electric, 1967-1970 and undated (Box 3)
    - Guest Quarters, undated (Box 3)
    - Globe Industries, undated (Box 3)
    - Hackney Bros. Body Co., undated (Box 3)
    - Hanes, 1972 and undated (Box 3)
    - IBM, 1967 and undated (Box 3)
    - J. Teague, undated (Box 3)
    - J.B. Long, Inc., undated (Box 3)
    - John Erwin Ramsay, undated (Box 3)
    - Life of Virginia, 1966 (Box 3)
    - Long Mfg. N.C. Inc., undated (Box 3)
    - Lyles, Bissett, Carlisle & Wolff, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Mallinckrodt, 1978-1979 and undated (Box 3)
    - Metropolitan Structures, undated (Box 3)
    - Microfilming Corporation of America, 1982 and undated (Box 3)
    - Millbrook, undated (Box 3)
    - Milree Publications, The Truth About Venereal Diseases, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Mitchell's Academy (hair styling school), undated (Box 3)
    - Newport News Shipbuilding, 1977-1980s (Box 3)
    - North Carolina Association of Broadcasting, 1986-1987 (Box 3)
    - North Carolina Equipment Co., 1971 (Box 3)
    - North Carolina Natural Gas, 1973-1987 (Box 3)
    - North Carolina Police Olympic Association, 1988 (Box 3)
    - Northern Telecom, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Oakwood Mobile Homes, 1980 (Box 3)
    - Parkway Homes, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Pembroke Meadows, undated (Box 3)
    - Perma-Tubes, undated (Box 3)
    - Public Service Company of North Carolina (PSNC), annual report, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Quail Hollow, undated (Box 3)
    - Raleigh-Durham Aviation, undated (Box 3)
    - Reynolds Aluminum, undated (Box 4)
    - R.J. Reynolds, 100th Anniversary, 1975 (Box 4)
    - Security Life and Trust, undated (Box 4)
    - Shriver & Holland, undated (Box 4)
    - Simpson Lee Paper Co., undated (Box 4)
    - Slim Jim (Goodmark Inc.), undated (Box 4)
    - Smallwood, undated (Box 4)
    - Smith-Douglass Nutro (Borden Chemical), undated (Box 4)
    - Snackpacker (United Snacks of America), undated (Box 4)
    - Southern States Cooperative, annual report, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Squire Store, undated (Box 4)
    - Stark Brothers, undated (Box 4)
    - Tega Cay, undated (Box 4)
    - Texasgulf, undated (Box 4)
    - Texize, Luther Leopard coloring book, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Textile World, 1974 (Box 4)
    - Tides Inn, undated (Box 4)
    - Tobacco Associates, American Tobacco publication (hard and soft cover), undated (Box 4)
    - Tobacco Associates, miscellaneous pamphlets, 1988 and undated (Box 4)
    - Triad Life Insurance, undated (Box 4)
    - Union Carbide, 1982 (Box 4)
    - U.S. Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Environmental Health Sciences, 1968 (Box 4)
    - U.S. Olympic Festival, Opening Ceremony program, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Vann Industries, undated (Box 4)
    - Village Green, undated (Box 4)
    - Virginia Press Association, 1959 (Box 4)
    - Wachovia, 1973 and undated (Box 4)
    - Washington Group, annual reports and other publications, 1973-1976 and undated (Box 4)
    - Weller, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Westminster-Canterbury, undated (Box 4)
    - Westinghouse, undated (Box 4)
    - WITN-TV7, rate card, 1968 (Box 4)
    - Woodrun, undated (Box 4)
  - Collateral literature examples, 1987 and undated (Box 5)
  - Designs
    - Business
      - ARH Realty, undated (Box 5)
      - Bigelow-Sanford, with correspondence and other papers,1979-1983 and undated (Box 5)
      - Book project, The Ordinary Becomes Extra Ordinary, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
      - For Members Only (advertising subscription service), banking industry examples, undated (Box 5)
      - Graphicsgroup Inc., Whistlin', 1975 (Box 5)
      - Hangchow Restaurant information for copy Wallace Kirby, undated (Box 5)
      - Hanson portfolio, undated (Box 5)
      - Module Builder notes, undated (Box 5)
      - People's Bank, undated (Box 5)
      - Snackpacker catchphrases, undated (Box 5)
      - South Carolina Electric & Gas, My Teacher's Got Me Stuck, comic book, with correspondence, 1957 (Box 5)
      - TGI Fridays, undated (Box 5)
      - Triangle Ice, undated (Box 5)
    - Food, undated (Box 5)
    - Historical, undated (Box 5)
    - Houses and furnishings, undated (Box 5)
    - Industrial, undated (Box 5)
    - Logos and typography, undated (Box 5)
    - Nature, undated (Box 5)
    - People, undated, (3 folders) (Box 5)
    - Tools and appliances, undated (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5)
  - Direct marketing examples, undated (Box 5)
  - Labels, Kingsdown, undated (Box 6)
  - Menus
    - Explorer Club, undated (Box 6)
    - Grill, undated (Box 6)
    - Pinehurst Hotel and Country Club, wine list, undated (Box 6)
    - RJ's, wine list, undated (Box 6)
    - Trade Mark Restaurant, undated (Box 6)
    - Wharf, Tampa General Hospital, undated (Box 6)
  - Photographs and slides
    - Agricultural, undated (Box 6)
    - Business and institutional, undated (Box 6)
    - Display and packaging, undated (Box 6)
    - Industrial, undated (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6)
    - People, undated (Box 6)
    - Slides, Bigelow figures, circa 1979-1983 (Box 6)
  - Print advertisements
    - A-G, 1973-1980 and undated (Box 6)
    - H-K, 1974-1976 and undated (Box 6)
    - L-P, 1969 and undated (Box 6)
    - R-S, 1976 and undated (Box 6)
    - Shakespeare (fishing equipment), undated (Box 6)
    - Slim Jim, undated (Box 6)
    - Target Flea and Tick, undated (Box 6)
    - Tobacco Associates, undated (Box 6)
    - U-W, 1984-1987 and undated (Box 6)
  - Stationery examples, undated (Box 6)
- Large-Format Items, 1963-1965 and undated, (5 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by format and title. Items are housed according to approximate size to prevent damage during storage.
  - Booklets
    - Apparel, Inc., Peaches 'n Cream catalogs, 1963-1965, (2 folders) (Box LF1)
    - Carolina Population Center, How People Plan Pregnancy, undated (Box LF1)
    - Carolina Population Center, Why People Plan Pregnancy, undated (Box LF1)
  - Collateral literature
    - Anytime Foods/Hobo, undated (Box LF1)
    - Hanes, undated (Box LF1)
    - Snackpacker, undated (Box LF1)
    - Quality Mills/Tog-a-longs, undated (Box LF1)
    - Topstyle lingerie, undated (Box LF1)
  - Designs
    - Business/Industry
      - Afex, undated (Box LF1)
      - Hangchow Restaurant, undated (Box LF1)
      - People's Bank, undated (Box LF1)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box LF1)
  - Logos and typography
    - Dukes of Hazzard, undated (Box LF1)
    - Raleigh Renaissance, undated (Box LF1)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, (2 folders) (Box LF1)
  - People, undated, (4 folders) (Box LF1)
  - Menus
    - Carolina Country Club (Box LF1)
    - Hangchow Restaurant, undated (Box LF1)
    - RJ's of Chapel Hill, undated (Box LF1)
    - RJ's Volkskeller, undated (Box LF1)
    - Wharf, Tampa General Hospital, undated (Box LF1)
  - Mounted designs
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box LF2)
    - People, undated (Box LF2)
    - Political/editorial cartoons, undated (Box LF3)
    - Print advertisements
      - G105-FM, undated (Box LF3)
      - Glass Plus cartoons, undated (Box LF3)
      - May Queen panty hose, undated (Box LF3)
      - Spray-n-Wash cartoons, undated (Box LF3)
      - Tobacco Associates, undated (Box LF3)
    - Logos/typography, undated (Box LF4)
    - Miscellaneous designs, undated (Box LF4)
    - People, undated (Box LF4)
    - Print advertisements
      - Bosch, undated (Box LF4)
      - McLean Trucking, undated (Box LF4)
  - Print advertisements (Box LF5)
    - Apparel Inc., undated (Box LF5)
    - Brook Hollow, undated (Box LF5)
    - Citizens and Southern, undated (Box LF5)
    - Colt Industries/Elox, undated (Box LF5)
    - Fort Bragg, undated (Box LF5)
    - General Electric, undated (Box LF5)
    - Heritage Furniture, undated (Box LF5)
    - James C. Greene Co., undated (Box LF5)
    - Jesse Jones, undated (Box LF5)
    - John Crosland Co., undated (Box LF5)
    - Kersey Manufacturing Co., undated (Box LF5)
    - Kings Down mattresses, undated (Box LF5)
    - L&L Machinery, undated (Box LF5)
    - McDonald's, undated (Box LF5)
    - McLean Trucking, undated (Box LF5)
    - Newport News Shipbuilding, undated (Box LF5)
    - North Carolina Mission, undated (Box LF5)
    - Reynolds Chemicals, undated (Box LF5)
    - Smith-Douglass, undated (Box LF5)
    - Smith's Transfer Company, undated (Box LF5)
    - Tobacco Associates, 1976 and undated (Box LF5)
    - Tog-a-Longs, undated (Box LF5)
    - Union National Bank, undated (Box LF5)
    - Victoria Place, undated (Box LF5)
    - Wachovia, undated (Box LF5)
    - Wadsworth Greenwood Associates, undated (Box LF5)
    - Wellco boots, undated (Box LF5)
    - Wellington Hall, undated (Box LF5)
- Oversize Materials, 1940-1989 and undated, (1 box)
  - Designs (Box OV1)
    - North Hills Shopping Center, undated (Box OV1)
    - Office scene, undated (Box OV1)
  - Ferree School of Art, article, 1950 (Box OV1)
  - Layout for a booklet, undated (Box OV1)
  - Print Advertisements
    - A Day of Solidarity with the Polish Nation, 1982 (Box OV1)
    - BTR Management, undated (Box OV1)
    - Colonial Chevrolet, undated (Box OV1)
    - Colorcraft, undated (Box OV1)
    - Dunedin, undated (Box OV1)
    - Ferree Studios, undated (Box OV1)
    - Forefathers (Williams Furniture), undated (Box OV1)
    - International Literacy Year, 1989 (Box OV1)
    - Liggett & Myers, 1976 (Box OV1)
    - McLean Trucking, undated (Box OV1)
    - NCNB (North Carolina National Bank), undated (Box OV1)
    - Northern Telecom, 1986 (Box OV1)
    - Nutro (Borden Chemical), 1967 (Box OV1)
    - Pembroke Meadows, undated (Box OV1)
    - Religious--American Bible Week, 1977 (Box OV1)
    - Religious--Scripture, undated (Box OV1)
    - Sweetheart Cups, 1974 (Box OV1)
    - Wellington Hall, undated (Box OV1)
  - Print Advertisements--Newspaper
    - Cardinal Corporation, 1974 (Box OV1)
    - Carolina Power & Light, 1944 (Box OV1)
    - FCB (First Citizens' Bank), 1975 (Box OV1)
    - Jesse Jones sausage, 1970 (Box OV1)
    - North Carolina Lawyers' Weekly, 1988 (Box OV1)
    - Parkwood Homes, undated (Box OV1)
    - Pembroke Meadows, 1987 and undated (Box OV1)
    - Pet Milk and Ice Cream, 1977 and undated (Box OV1)
    - Rose's Department Store, undated (Box OV1)
    - Wachovia, undated (Box OV1)
  - Ferree Studios, Christmas wrapping paper design, undated (Box OV1, Folder 1)
  - Print advertisements/posters
    - American Bible Week, 1977 (Box OV1)
    - Busch Gardens, 1983 (Box OV1)
    - Liggett & Myers, 1978 (Box OV1)
    - North Carolina Building and Loan League, 1940 (Box OV1)
    - Pickering sportswear, undated (Box OV1)
    - Sweetheart Cups, 1974 (Box OV1)
    - Target Flea and Tick, undated (Box OV1)
    - Wachovia, undated (Box OV1)
    - Wellington Hall, undated (Box OV1)